[
    {
        "front": "tensor",
        "back": "A mathematical object that can be represented by an indexed collection of numbers, where the number of indices (i.e., the order) can be greater than 1."
    },
    {
        "front": "matrix",
        "back": "A tensor of order two; a matrix can be visualized as a two-dimensional array of numbers."
    },
    {
        "front": "square matrix",
        "back": "A matrix for which the number of rows equals the number of columns."
    },
    {
        "front": "main diagonal",
        "back": "For an $m \\times m$ matrix, the <I>main diagonal</I> or <I>principal diagonal</I> is the vector of \\(m\\) elements at the indices \\(k, k\\) for \\(k=0,1,\\ldots, m-1\\)."
    },
    {
        "front": "diagonal matrix",
        "back": "A square matrix  for which the only nonzero components are along the main diagonal."
    },
    {
        "front": "upper triangular matrix",
        "back": "A square \\(m \\times m\\) matrix is an <I>upper triangular matrix</I> if its only nonzero elements are in the main diagonal and above; in other words, the only nonzero elements are those at  positions \\(k,l\\) that satisfy \\(l \\ge k\\)."
    },
    {
        "front": "lower triangular matrix",
        "back": "A square \\(m \\times m\\) matrix is a <I>lower triangular matrix</I> if its only nonzero elements are in the main diagonal and below; in other words, the only nonzero elements are those at positions \\(k,l\\) that satisfy \\(l \\le k\\)."
    },
    {
        "front": "triangular matrix",
        "back": "A square \\(m \\times m\\) matrix (two-dimensional array) that is an upper triangular matrix or lower triangular matrix."
    },
    {
        "front": "zeros matrix",
        "back": "A matrix of all zeros."
    },
    {
        "front": "ones matrix",
        "back": "A matrix of all ones."
    },
    {
        "front": "identity matrix",
        "back": "A diagonal matrix in which the off-diagonal entries are all zero and the diagonal entries are all equal to 1. The \\(m \\times  m\\) identity matrix is denoted \\(\\mathbf{I}_m\\). If $I_{j,k}$ denotes the entry in row $j$ and column $k$, then $I_{j,k}=1$ if $j=k$ and $I_{j,k}=0$ if  $j \\ne k$."
    }
]

